[
  {
    "question": "The “Father of Artificial Intelligence” is:",
    "answer": "John McCarthy is also known as the “Father of Artificial Intelligence”.",
    "options": [
      "Alan Turing",
      "Charles Babbage",
      "John McCarthy",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Blind Search can be used for which of the following situations?",
    "answer": "Blind Search doesn’t contain any domain information such as closeness and hence it is best used for a Small Search Space.",
    "options": [
      "Real-Life Simulation",
      "Small Search Space",
      "Advanced Game Theory",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "In how many category processes is Artificial Intelligence classified in?",
    "answer": "AI is classified into 3 categories processes: Sensing, Reasoning, and Acting.",
    "options": [
      "Depends on the input nature",
      "5",
      "2",
      "3"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "If a machine can change its course of action based on the external environment on its own, the machine is called?",
    "answer": "Machines that can change their course of action by making their own decisions are said to be Intelligent.",
    "options": [
      "Mobile",
      "Intelligent",
      "Both A and B",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the common language for Artificial Intelligence?",
    "answer": "While programming can be done in any language, in today’s world Python has become the go-to language for AI and ML-related tasks due to its vast and diverse library functionalities.",
    "options": [
      "Python",
      "Java",
      "Lisp",
      "PHP"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not an application of artificial intelligence?",
    "answer": "Other than Database Management System, all the other options are viable fields of study in Artificial Intelligence.",
    "options": [
      "Computer Vision",
      "Natural Language Processing",
      "Database Management System",
      "Digital Assistants"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The proposition symbols in AI are?",
    "answer": "true and false are the 2 proposition symbols in AI.",
    "options": [
      "true and false",
      "true, false, and null",
      "true",
      "false"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following symbols in AI are logical symbols?",
    "answer": "The logical symbols in AI are: Negation, Conjunction, Disjunction, Implication, and Biconditional symbols.",
    "options": [
      "Negation",
      "Conjunction",
      "Implication",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are informed search methods?",
    "answer": "All of the above options are informed search methods used in Artificial Intelligence.",
    "options": [
      "Best First Search",
      "A* Search",
      "Memory Bound Heuristic Search",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The name of the Artificial Intelligence system developed by Daniel Bobrow was?",
    "answer": "The name of the Artificial Intelligence system developed by Daniel Bobrow was STUDENT developed in the Lisp Language in 1964.",
    "options": [
      "BACON",
      "SIMD",
      "STUDENT",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a type of artificial intelligence agent?",
    "answer": "There are a total of 5 AI agents: Simple Reflex Agent, Model-Based Reflex Agent, Goal-based reflex agent, utility-based agent, learning agent.",
    "options": [
      "Learning AI Agent",
      "Simple Reflex AI Agent",
      "Goal-Based AI Agent",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "How many types of recognition are there in AI?",
    "answer": "There are 3 types of recognition in AI: Biometric Identification, Content-Based Image Retrieval, Handwriting Recognition.",
    "options": [
      "5",
      "3",
      "2",
      "1"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Procedural Domain Knowledge in a rule-based system, is in the form of?",
    "answer": "Procedural Domain Knowledge in a rule-based system, is in the form of Production Rules.",
    "options": [
      "Meta-Rules",
      "Control Rules",
      "Production Rules",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the different types of Artificial Intelligence approaches?",
    "answer": "All the given options are different types of AI approaches used in different scenarios.",
    "options": [
      "Strong Approach",
      "Weak Approach",
      "Applied Approach",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "‘The Imitation Game’ was the original name of?",
    "answer": "The Turing Test was originally called the ‘The Imitation Game’ by its creator.",
    "options": [
      "LISP",
      "The Turing Test",
      "The Halting Problem",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following architecture is also known as systolic arrays?",
    "answer": "MISD architecture is also known as systolic arrays.",
    "options": [
      "MISD",
      "SISD",
      "SIMD",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Decisions of Victory/Defeat are made in Game trees using which algorithm?",
    "answer": "The Min/Max algorithm is preferred over other search-based algorithms in Game trees to make win/loss decisions optimally.",
    "options": [
      "DFS",
      "BFS",
      "Heuristic Search",
      "Min/Max Algorithm"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The correct ways to solve a problem of state-space search are?",
    "answer": "The only 2 ways to solve a problem of state-space search problem are given in options (A) and (B).",
    "options": [
      "Forward from the initial state",
      "Backward from the goal",
      "Both A and B",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Machines running LISP are also called?",
    "answer": "Machines running LISP are also called AI workstations.",
    "options": [
      "AI Workstations",
      "Time-Sharing Terminals",
      "Both A and B",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "How does an AI agent interacts with its environment?",
    "answer": "An AI agent perceives and acts upon the environment using Sensors and Actuators. With Sensors, it senses the surrounding, and with Actuators, it acts on it.",
    "options": [
      "Using sensors and perceivers",
      "Using only sensors",
      "Using only perceivers",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the work of Task Environment and Rational Agents?",
    "answer": "Task Environments provides an issue and Rational Agents provides the corresponding solution.",
    "options": [
      "Problem and Solution",
      "Solution and Problem",
      "Observation and Problem",
      "Observation and Solution"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "How many types of observing environments are there?",
    "answer": "There are 2 types of observing environments: Fully and Partial.",
    "options": [
      "2",
      "3",
      "1",
      "0"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "How many types of quantification are there in AI?",
    "answer": "There are 2 types of quantification in AI: Universal and Existential.",
    "options": [
      "1",
      "2",
      "3",
      "4"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Out of the given options, which of the following algorithms uses the least memory?",
    "answer": "DFS uses the lesser amount of memory because at a time the path from the node to a root is only stored in the memory stack unlike BFS which will have to store the whole tree within it.",
    "options": [
      "DFS",
      "BFS",
      "Both A and B are the same",
      "Cannot be compared"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Machines that try to imitate human intuition while handling vague information lie in the field of AI called?",
    "answer": "Fuzzy Logic allows machines to mimic human intuition when provided with information that is vague in nature.",
    "options": [
      "Functional Logic",
      "Fuzzy Logic",
      "Boolean Logic",
      "Human Logic"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant by a “Complete Algorithm”?",
    "answer": "A complete algorithm is an algorithm that finds a solution to a problem(if it exists) in finite time.",
    "options": [
      "If a solution exists, the algorithm will find it before terminating.",
      "It will find the solution in a finite amount of time.",
      "Both A and B.",
      "None of the above."
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The measure of performance of an AI agent is measured using?",
    "answer": "The performance of an AI agent is improved using the learning agent.",
    "options": [
      "Learning Agent.",
      "Changing Agent.",
      "Both A and B.",
      "None of the above."
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are valid Machine Learning algorithms?",
    "answer": "All of the above algorithms given above are valid ML algorithms.",
    "options": [
      "Linear Regression",
      "K Means Clustering",
      "Naive Bayes",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What are different machine learning methods?",
    "answer": "The machine learning methods include Memorization, Analogy, and Deduction.",
    "options": [
      "Memorization",
      "Analogy",
      "Deduction",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Exploratory Learning is another name for?",
    "answer": "In unsupervised learning, no external supervision is required so the machine learns on the basis of exploring the datasets themselves.",
    "options": [
      "Supervised learning",
      "Unsupervised learning",
      "Reinforcement learning",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The things considered in the design of a learning element are?",
    "answer": "The 3 main things to be considered in the design of a learning element are: Components, Feedback, and Representation.",
    "options": [
      "Components",
      "Feedback",
      "Representation",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The different types of machine learning are?",
    "answer": "The 3 types of machine learning are: Supervised, Unsupervised, and Reinforcement Learning.",
    "options": [
      "Supervised",
      "Unsupervised",
      "Reinforcement",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "How is a decision reached upon by a decision tree?",
    "answer": "A decision tree makes its decision based on the results of a sequence of tests.",
    "options": [
      "No test",
      "Single Test",
      "Double Test",
      "Multiple sequences of tests"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "A hybrid Bayesian Network consists of?",
    "answer": "Discrete and Continuous variables both act as numerical inputs to a hybrid Bayesian network.",
    "options": [
      "Discrete Variables",
      "Continuous Variables",
      "Both A and B",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "AI agents are composed of?",
    "answer": "AI agents implement mapping for perceptions to actions.",
    "options": [
      "Architecture",
      "Program",
      "Both A and B",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "For external action selection, which element is used in the agent?",
    "answer": "The performance element is used for external action selection in AI agents.",
    "options": [
      "Perceive",
      "Performance",
      "Actuator",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the brightness of a pixel on the screen increased?",
    "answer": "The brightness of a pixel is directly proportional to the amount of light incident on the screen.",
    "options": [
      "Increasing the amount of light directed on the screen",
      "Using mirrors",
      "Using sound waves",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The process of making 2 logical expressions look identical is called?",
    "answer": "Unification is the process of making 2 logical expressions look identical.",
    "options": [
      "Lifting",
      "Unification",
      "Both A and B",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "PEAS is an abbreviation for?",
    "answer": "PEAS is an abbreviation for Performance, Environment, Actuators, Sensors.",
    "options": [
      "Peace, Environment, Action, Sense",
      "Peer, Environment, Actuators, Sensors",
      "Performance, Environment, Actuators, Sensors",
      "Performance, Environment, Actuators, Sense"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Knowledge in AI can be represented as?",
    "answer": "The representation of knowledge in AI can be done both as Predicate and Propositional Logic.",
    "options": [
      "Predicate Logic",
      "Propositional Logic",
      "Both A and B",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are appropriate levels for a knowledge-based AI agent?",
    "answer": "The 3 main levels for a knowledge-based AI agent are: Knowledge, Logical, and Implementation level.",
    "options": [
      "Knowledge Level",
      "Logical Level",
      "Implementation Level",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "How can we achieve Artificial Intelligence in real life?",
    "answer": "Machine learning and Deep Learning are 2 of the ways to implement Artificial Intelligence in real life.",
    "options": [
      "Machine Learning",
      "Deep Learning",
      "Both A and B",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are heuristic search algorithms?",
    "answer": "Both options A and B are heuristics-based search algorithms.",
    "options": [
      "Best First Search Algorithm",
      "A* Search Algorithm",
      "Both A and B",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "How do we multiply 2 numbers in LISP?",
    "answer": "The syntax to multiply 2 numbers in LISP is correctly shown in option A.",
    "options": [
      "* a b",
      "a * b",
      "a mul b",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Inference engines work on the principle of?",
    "answer": "The modes on which inference engines work are forward and backward chaining.",
    "options": [
      "Backward Chaining",
      "Forward Chaining",
      "Both A and B",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The process of breaking an image into parts is called?",
    "answer": "Segmentation is the process of breaking an image into groups based on the similarity of pixels.",
    "options": [
      "Smoothing",
      "Segmentation",
      "Processing",
      "Break Down"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are valid 3D image processing techniques?",
    "answer": "All of the above options are valid 3D image processing techniques.",
    "options": [
      "Motion",
      "Texture",
      "Contour",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Parsing is used for?",
    "answer": "The process of building up a parse tree for an input string is called parsing.",
    "options": [
      "Parse tree buildup",
      "Data Interpretation",
      "Sound Recognition",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Artificial Intelligence is associated with computers of which generation?",
    "answer": "Fifth Generation computers are said to be able to have Artificial Intelligence within them.",
    "options": [
      "Second",
      "First",
      "Fifth",
      "Third"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Components of an expert system are?",
    "answer": "All the above options comprise the components of an expert system.",
    "options": [
      "Knowledge base",
      "User interface",
      "Inference engine",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following search method takes less memory space?",
    "answer": "Depth First Search takes the least memory consumption because only the nodes on the current path are stored.",
    "options": [
      "Depth First Search",
      "Breadth-First Search",
      "Linear Search",
      "Optimal Search"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a type of AI?",
    "answer": "Reactive Machines are not a type of AI based on functionality.",
    "options": [
      "Weak AI",
      "Theory of Mind",
      "Reactive Machines",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What is state space in AI?",
    "answer": "State Space in AI is defined as the collection of all the problem states.",
    "options": [
      "Collection of all the problem states.",
      "A specific problem states out of all the problem states.",
      "Both A and B.",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  }
]